Rudra Dutt

Overview

Business Intelligence Analyst with over three years of experience. Delivered projects with 100% completion, over ~90% of which were on time, and less than ~5% needed rework. Demonstrated experience in Business and Functional requirement gathering. Have worked with several business intelligence technologies including Power BI, Tableau, and Google Studio.

Skills

SQL | Power BI | Tableau | MS Excel | MS Powerpoint | AWS S3 | Azure Data Lake AWS Redshift | Python | Data Studio | Data Mining | ETL Tools | Data Visualization Data Analysis

Professional Experience

03/2020 - present

Business Intelligence Analyst

Innovation Junction LLC

- Developing new logical reports and participating in automation projects using Power BI, Tableau, and cloud technologies.
- Optimizing the process of scheduling the manpower for the inventory operations process
- Migrating data from Oracle database to AWS Redshift and S3 bucket using AWS CLI
- Using multiple data analysis, ETL, and BI tools to provide daily, weekly and monthly analysis related to monitoring: Sales Analysis, Customer Rationalization, Product Profitability, Financial reports, and Inventory monitoring reports.
- Created an application that helped in reducing the variance of forecast to 2%
- Creation and monitoring of targets, KPIs, and forecasts periodically
- Responsible for delivery and maintenance of standard quality reports for engaged business partners on key metrics and performance measures
- Recommend actions by analyzing and interpreting data and making comparative analyses

06/2019 - 02/2020

Management Trainee

Karvy Stock Broking Ltd

- Utilized strong decision-making and technical knowledge to cater to clients who needed buy/sell recommendations in the stock market
- Worked to build long-term relationships with clients by problem-solving around their pain points
- Managed client's portfolio of stocks to maximize profit
- Worked to support the company mission and adhere to company protocol at all times
- Worked with cross-functional teams to structure problems, identify appropriate data sources, extract data and utilize them for solving problems

Education

2017 – 2019 Ranchi

Masters in Business Administration

Central University of Jharkhand Major in Marketing